# Tony Gama

# **REACT FULL STACK DEVELOPER**

## **ACHIEVEMENTS**

- 1. Developed a Full Stack Application with Python and React
- 2. Upgraded an Existing Application's Frontend by 30%
- 3. Integrated 3 External APIs into an Application
- 4. Reduced Development Time of New Features by 50%
- 5. Launched 5 Projects Utilizing Different Tech Stacks

# **EXPERIENCE**

# **FULL-STACK LEAD DEVELOPER**

Apr 2022 – PRESENT Plego Technologies, Houston, TX

- Translated designs into user-friendly responsive web interfaces with React, Gatsby, Vue, and Python.
- Developed a new component in React that was used to define complex conditions based on field values, used throughout the application in many features.
- Oversaw the creation of coding standards and started a discussion about code quality management in the company.
- Designed and implemented a tax statement's administrative app using React (front end and back end).
- Developed software that extracted data from hundreds of thousands of PDF documents about insurance plans, then organized the extracted data to provide reports to business owners.

Technologies: Python, Django, Flask, React, Vue, SCSS, Agile, SQL, RabbitMQ, Zoho API, CSS, .NET, JavaScript, C#, Git, HTML5, .NET Core, C#.NET, APIs, Front-end, Full-stack, Architecture, REST APIs, Best Practices, Object-oriented Programming (OOP), Software Design Patterns

# **FULL-STACK DEVELOPER**

Apr 2021 – Apr 2022 Tempora, Houston, TX

- Created a CMS with a Node.js-based back end and React-based front end that was presented to clients, as an evolution of the current solution.
- Worked on creating tools that set up the supply pipeline—finding builders with the skills that clients needed.
- Worked on the pipeline efficiency to process files with thousands of lines efficiently and asynchronously, using microservices and 3rd-party services.

## CONTACT

tonygmstar@gmail.com (713) 955-7635 www.linkedin.com/in/tonygama-it Houston, TX

# **ABOUT ME**

A full-stack / front end developer who started with React and Python Django as his chosen framework and, more recently, worked mainly with Node.js and .NET. Proficient in Vue, Angular and Next.js. Am a quick learner, willing and able to learn new skills rapidly, and is experienced in working in a multinational environment. Have cooperated with teams and clients from US and various European countries.

# **EDUCATION**

St. Edward's University, 2018 Master's in Computer Science

University of Texas at Dallas, 2015 Bachelor's in Computer Science

- Developed a front-end internal tooling platform in React to give access to all the tools the team built to the other employees in the company.
- Migrated AngularJS SPA to React and Redux, improving performance significantly.
- Designed and developed key parts of an API gateway and nine microservices based on Django, Flask, backed by PostgreSQL and deployed in a Kubernetes cluster.
- Provided technical expertise and insights to direct troubleshooting efforts and solution development.

Technologies: Django, Node.js, TypeScript, React, Angular, Express.js, Amazon Web Services (AWS), Kubernetes, CSS, JavaScript, Git, HTML5, Redux, Front-end, Full-stack, CI/CD Pipelines, Tailwind CSS, OAuth, Architecture, Redux Toolkit, PostgreSQL, REST APIs, Best Practices, Python, Object-oriented Programming (OOP), Software Design Patterns

# SENIOR REACT, VUE, ANGULAR, AND PYTHON DEVELOPER

May 2018 – Apr 2021 TekRevol

- Developed core features and dashboards for the "My Therapy Assistant" mental health platform using React with Redux and Styled Components on the front-end, while also implementing order processing and payment APIs using Django and PostgreSQL on the back-end, helping thousands of small businesses to efficiently manage product listings, orders and inventory on the platform.
- Developed and maintained both front-end and back end layer of Parts Source's platform using Python and React.
- Cooperated with the designers and back-end developers to ensure the proper quality of the provided solution.
- Implemented server-side rendering for the React application using Next.is.
- Created a drag-and-drop, React-based static site generator with reusable web components.
- Provided UI expertise with Angular and React to troubleshoot existing UI problems and build new user-friendly forms—revamping the user experience.
- Reduced the size of the data access layer by 50%.
- Introduced automated E2E testing to facilitate regression testing for each push to QA.
- Maintained and developed a Microsft SQL database and an API in Node.js that utilized this database.
- Mentored the team and enforced Scrum principles, ensuring the Scrum process's quality.

Technologies: React, .NET, Vue, Angular, Redux, CSS, JavaScript, C#, Git, Agile, HTML5, ASP.NET Web API, .NET Core, C#.NET, Front-end, Full-stack, CI/CD Pipelines, OAuth, REST APIs, Azure DevOps, Best Practices, Object-oriented Programming (OOP), Software Design Patterns

## **REACT FRONT END DEVELOPER**

Apr 2017 – May 2018 Screenlink Technologies

- Provided analysis about performance and recommended different solutions and gained a 300% faster build time and reduced by 200% the memory usage.
- Created a custom component library with React-styled components, and Storybook, including packaging and publishing with Lerna and Rollup, saving development time for almost 65 components and common utils functions.

# **SKILLS**

# Languages

TypeScript, CSS, HTML5, JavaScript, Python, HTML, SQL, SCSS, C#, PHP

#### **Frameworks**

Django, Flask, .NET, .NET Core, ASP.NET Web API, Entity, Swagger, Angular, ADO.NET, Node.js, Express.js, Redux, Next.js, Tailwind CSS, ASP.NET Core, Windows Communication Framework (WCF), ASP.NET MVC, ASP.NET MVC 5, Knockout (Knockout.js), Windows Presentation Foundation (WPF), ASP.NET

# Libraries/APIs

React, Vue, Vue 2, Node.js, REST APIs, jQuery, AutoMapper, Zoho API, Entity Framework, Web API 2

#### Tools

Git, Bitbucket, Jenkins, TeamCity, Azure DevOps Services, Jira, Visual Studio, Gulp, RabbitMQ

# **Paradigms**

Agile, Scrum, REST, Best Practices, Object-oriented Programming (OOP), FluentValidation, Azure DevOps

## **Platforms**

Visual Studio Code (VS Code), Software Design Patterns, Amazon Web Services (AWS), Azure, Windows, Kubernetes

# Other

MVC Frameworks, WCF Web Services, GitFlow, APIs, Front-end, Front-end Development, Full-stack, CI/CD Pipelines, Episerver, Cloud, User Interface (UI), OAuth, Architecture, Redux Toolkit, Octopus Deploy

## Storage

MSSQLCE, PostgreSQL, Microsoft SQL Server, IBM Db2 - Implemented the database logic and APIs to support a new pricing model for TotalJobs Recruiter Platform, the UK's largest job site. Built the front end in React.

Technologies: React, jQuery, Microsoft SQL Server, ASP.NET Core, CSS, .NET, JavaScript, C#, Git, Agile, Scrum, HTML5, ASP.NET Web API, C#.NET, CI/CD Pipelines, OAuth, REST APIs, Best Practices, Object-oriented Programming (OOP), Software Design Patterns

### **ASSOCIATE FRONT END DEVELOPER**

Aug 2016 – Apr 2017 Screenlink Technologies

- Maintained and conducted workshops for a desktop application facilitating the financial reporting process.
- Developed multiple web apps used for gathering financial data from users.
- Contributed to the statutory financial audit as an auditor, gaining knowledge about accounting processes.
- Learned how to write optimized component structure using React,
- Worked with a systems engineer to gain an understanding of network security and maintainable infrastructure, including AWS.

Technologies: React, jQuery, Microsoft SQL Server, Entity Framework, ASP.NET MVC, Windows Communication Framework (WCF), Windows Presentation Foundation (WPF), CSS, .NET, JavaScript, C#, HTML5, C#.NET, Front-end, Full-stack, REST APIs, Object-oriented Programming (OOP)

# CERTIFICATIONS

# **SEPTEMBER 2020 - PRESENT**

Microsoft Certified Solutions Associate Web Applications Microsoft

# **AUGUST 2018 - AUGUST 2013**

Microsoft Certified Solutions Developer Web Applications Microsoft

# **JULY 2018 - PRESENT**

Microsoft Specialist: Programming in HTML5 with JavaScript and CSS3 Microsoft